SUDESHNA BHATTACHARYA

E-MAIL: SUDESHNABH@GMAIL.COM, SUDESHNA.BHATTACHARYA@CNETWORK.CO.IN H-1584, 2ND FLOOR, CHITTARANJAN PARK, NEW DELHI – 110019 Tel: +91 11 41603400, MOBILE: +91 9810147802 DOB: 31 MAY 1979

SUMMARY

I am a Human Resource Management professional with extensive experience in HR functions which include recruitment of professionals starting from the middle management right up to the functional heads across all industries. Apart from Handling end to end recruitment cycle, I have also handled compensation & benefits, payroll processing, employee engagement, employee relations, on-boarding of the candidate ensuring proper culture fit in the organisation. Leading a team of HR professionals who are the best talents in the industry. In addition, I have significant experience in recruiting talent for Non-Banking Financial Businesses, IT & ITES, Education and Research, Hospitality, bulk hirings for Legal Process Outsourcing Firms, BPO's, Construction and Engineering, FMCG etc to name a few and am well conversant with operations management systems such as Siebel, System5 (Hyperion), Finesse, Standard Banking System (SBS) and spreadsheet-based analysis. I have also been handling forecasting, maintaining actuals, collections, MIS reporting, commercials and back-end processing. I am multi-lingual and have excellent diction and communication skills and have very good organizational skills. I have over 15 + years of working experience.

EDUCATION

2004	MA in Management	Durham University, UK
2002	Financial Computer Applications	ICWA, New Delhi,
2001	Bachelor of Commerce	Calcutta University
1998	Senior Secondary School	Modern High School For Girls,
	Kolkata	~

WORK EXPERIENCE

ZERONE MICROSYSTEMS PVT. LTD (CARDSSE)

(AUG 2017 - MAR 2022)

Was working at Zerone at the capacity of Director- Human Resources ensuring optimum utilisation of the existing manpower and implementing strategies in order to scale up productivity by hiring the best talents in the industry. Ensuring in maintaining proper employee relations and culture fit of the employees. Making the on-boarding process of the candidate innovative and interactive and eventually converting him/her into a valuable asset of the company. Leading a team of professionals to ensure that the company's goals and objectives are achieved.

The area of responsibilities included:

- Responsible for ensuring optimal utilisation of budget allotted for the different roles across funtions.
- Responsible for P&L of the Business Line and ensuring its success
- Developing and Implementing Human Resource Policies
- Ensuring compliance with HR Laws
- Supporting strategic objectives
- Recruiting and Negotiating employee agreements
- Employee Engagement
- Mentoring and Motivating the existing team of professionals

- Introducing workshops and trainings in order to upgrade the skill sets of the teams.

C NETWORK

(Nov 2006 - June 2017)

Setup the firm and led a team of 11 HR professionals to recruit best of breed middle management talent for clients that included Rolls Royce, DLF Hotels, United Lex, Bechtel, Godfrey Philips, Hilton Hotels, Coke, Indian Institute of Management, Ahmedabad, Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay and many more prestigious clients

The area of responsibilities included:

- Responsible for National Level recruitment for different clients
 - Taking care of overall Retail & Non Retail recruitment for the company comprising all Functional recruitment
 - Indepth understanding of Retail as well as non Retail Business
 - Interacting with Business Leaders/Functional Managers for recruitment on day to day basis
 - Creating reports and MIS
 - Managing a Team of recruiters
 - Recruiting as per the SLA defined and shortest TAT(Turnaround Time)
 - Implementing recruitment plan as per agreed time frame for all customers
 - Working within available budget as per Business plan
 - Administering different selection tools and techniques for different business formats
 - Reducing low value adding processes to minimize lead time
 - Work towards generating higher conversions
 - Putting together job descriptions for all positions along with all clients
 - Headhunting different positions using networks over and above the usual job portals, referrals and the other mediums of advertisement.
- Tie up with verification agencies for verification and exit of candidates.
 - -Adhering to very strict deadlines and shortest possible turnaround times in order to contribute indirectly in achieving our clients goals and objectives.
- Providing best of breed professionals so that not only the company gains but even the individual growth opportunities are enhanced.

ERICSSON LTD

(Dec 2005 – Sep 2006)

Continued with the same responsibilities as in Marconi Telecommunications as Marconi was bought over by Ericsson.

MARCONI TELECOMMUNICATIONS PVT LTD

(September 2004 – Dec 2005)

Assistant Manager, HR & Operations, responsible for all human resource requirements and management reporting of the sales process and collating the critical indicators of sales.

- •Supporting recruitment process
- •Handling the whole Hr operations, reporting directly to the Asia Pacific head, in terms of getting approvals on head counts, budgeting for the increased head count, training

- programs, orientation of the new joinees, employee relations, performance management.
- •Reducing dependency of External consultants/vendors in the hiring process in turn reducing companies cost.
- •Bench-marking Hiring Costs(to be competitive).
- •Managing performance SLA of Consultants and Vendors.
- •Coordination with various stakeholders of the operations process
- •Preparation of customer analysis report reflecting the actuals and forecast sales
- •Generation of Weekly Report having the operations forecast
- •Managing invoices and Purchase orders of the operations
- •Preparation of Bond Forecast Report stating the details of the issue of the Bond

AMERICAN EXPRESS

(March 2003 – Jan 2004)

Executive Trainee at American Express non-Card lending division.

- •Responsible for credit card default management operations
- •Managing the process of booking the customer cases into the system to the final dispatching of manager's cheques
- •Making MIS's for representing the amount of business and top up cases
- •Overseeing preparation of manager's cheques, re-booking loan, canceling previous loan, handling post dated cheque clearance and authorization of the same.
- •Settlement of manager's cheques in Finnesse.
- •Prior to working for the non-card lending division, I was in the card division where my responsibilities included processing of applications of credit cards, De-duping and detecting inconsistent and suspicious transactions

CITIFINANCIALS (FORMERLY THE ASSOCIATES)

(May 2002 – January 2003)

The Associates is one of the largest assets financing company in the world. It is one of the subsidiaries of Citigroup. I am currently responsible for the back-end of auto loans. Earlier, I was working in the commercial department and I was responsible for MIS and customer follow-up. My activities include the following:

- •Responsible for creating the OLV provisions MIS reflecting the criticality of each asset condition and maintenance budget for the same.
- •Budgeting for the delinquent cases moving into collections.
- •Developing MIS for Accounts Receivables
- •Early warning and watch-list of delinquent cases and loss forecasting
- •Following up with clients for post-finance asset ownership documents
- •Following up on payment collections from bucket cases moving into collections.
- •Maintaining databases of the customer account status and asset details, involving loss provisioning and depreciation.
- •Backend Processing for Auto Sales department that include processing of files, approval of loans and operations tracking.
- •Responsible for approval of loans with a ticket size of 1crore plus.
- Collections tracking

SOUTH ASIA CONSULTANTS (www.southasiaconsultants.com)

(March 2001 to May 2002)

South Asia Consultants is a startup and specializes in recruitment support for middle-east firms. I was one of the founding partners of the firm.

- •Starting up the firm and getting the first clients
- •Recruiting support staff
- •Maintaining the firm's accounts
- Tracking Receivables

TECHNOLOGY EXPOSURE

OFFICE PRODUCTIVITY: Word, Excel spreadsheet, Lotus Spreadsheet, PowerPoint

DATABASE: Dbase, MS AccessOperating

SYSTEM: Windows 95/NT, DOS, Windows 2000, Linux INTERNET-RELATED: Internet Browser, MS FrontPage, Web designing

FINANCE RELATED: Finesse, E.X. Next Generation (TCS package), Standard

Banking System (SBS), CRM and Enterprise Systems, Siebel,

System5 (Hyperion)

COMMUNICATION

Attended workshop on electronic media organized by IAAN Creations, with focus on communication skills

LANGUAGES

English, Hindi, Tamil, Bangla, French

REFERENCES

To be furnished on request